# Jonathan D. Bean

jdbean@jdbean.net | https://jdbean.net

Full stack web developer with a passion for engineering and refining technical systems. With experience in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and React as well as a background in Law and Open Source Software. I possess strong skills in project management and creative problem-solving as well as a broad understanding of the modern software landscape that help companies design and implement innovative software solutions to satisfy customer needs.

## TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Ex-Static - Source Code | Demo

Turn any Jekyll blog into a Content Management System with a user-friendly interface for authors and editors

- Combined Semantic-UI and Custom SASS/CSS to design frontend
- · Packaged project as a Ruby Gem to ease reuse of code in multiple sites
- · Configured Sinatra to provide a JSON API backend
- Utilized React to create a performant single-page-application frontend

Lend-to-Friend - Source Code | Demo

A peer-to-peer lending community where users can post, lend, and borrow items

- · Combined Bootstrap and Custom CSS to produce a responsively designed frontend
- · Configured Devise to ensure authentication/authorization of users throughout the site
- Employed ChartKick and HighChart.js to provide site analytics

PROTOCOL - Source Code (Front-End) | Source Code (Back-End) | Demo

A real-time chat application that allows for seamless real-time multi-party multi-lingual conversations

- · Configured ActionCable to provide real-time web-socket based text communications
- Integrated with Google APIs to provide at will translation of text
- Employed ActiveRecord to ensure persistence of channel messages between sessions

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, Semantic UI, AWS, Heroku, LATEX, Linux, Docker

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Law Office of Jonathan D. Bean, New York, NY

Principal Counsel, April 2016-Present

Counsel technology-oriented clients on matters including licensing, trademark, copyright, patent, privacy and data-security law. Conducted review of open source license compliance obligations, policies, and practices for client WordPress.com and developed open source compliance documentation for reference by company employees.

SOFTWARE FREEDOM LAW CENTER, New York, NY

Counsel, October 2013–July 2016 | Legal Fellow, October 2012–October 2013 | Law Clerk, May 2011–August 2011 Advised developers, users, and distributors of open source software. Audited software products for compliance with open source software license conditions and export control regulations. Authored briefs amicus curiae submitted before the United States Supreme Court. Represented firm at industry conferences and working groups. Hired and supervised interns, junior attorneys, and staff.

#### **EDUCATION**

FLATIRON SCHOOL, New York, NY – Software Engineering Immersive, June 2018

Description: Intensive full stack web development training emphasizing Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and React.

New York University Law School, New York, NY - J.D., May 2012

Bar Admission: New York State, 2012

Honors: New York University Journal of Law & Liberty

Senior Articles Editor, 2011-2012 | Staff Editor, 2010-2011

THE GEORGE WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY, Washington D.C. - B.A. in Political Science, May 2008

Honors: Degree awarded magna cum laude